Julie Rodríguez López

Mobile: (+57) 3175793396 • ingall2014@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/julie-rodriguezlopez/ Bogota, Colombia

OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT, PROJECTS, CONTINUOUS IMPROVEMENT AND CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE.

Bilingual Industrial Engineer, expert in the area of operations with a master's degree in Business Administration (MBA). Fifteen years of experience in the logistics, pharmaceutical, industrial and E-commerce sectors, leading teams, projects, planning, and continuous improvement focused on the customer experience.

Extensive experience leading operational areas such as warehousing, transportation, customer service, and implementing projects in each of these areas from planning to closing.

Among my skills, I highlight the ability to solve problems and make decisions assertively, my highly proactive way of working, leadership and teamwork with different areas of the organization, my ability to adapt easily to changes and to be in constant learning. These skills have been developed in the coordination of large projects and the launch of operations with teams of up to 500 people.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Enfeter S.A Volunteering

Dec 2022- Present

IPS of Home Services nationwide 850 patients.

Audit and improvement of operational processes.

- CRM implementation from tendering, integration, implementation, process change, user training and customer communication.
- Coordination of customer service area.
- Accompaniment throughout the customer experience process, raising opportunities for improvement and project development.

Shopee Feb 2022- Sept 2022

Client Solution Manager

- Responsible for building a consultative solution for our clients based on data.
- Responsible for projects, planning and continuous improvement in order to improve customer experienced.
- Design all the customer journey and follow up to post selling process.
- Tracking kpi's and finding insights to drive "test and learn" mindset in clients.
- Training and negotiation of Clients (Sellers) to improve our processes efficiency.

Dafiti Group Feb 2019-Feb 2022

LATAM Customer Experience Manager.

Leader of the customer service area at a regional level (Chile, Colombia, Argentina) focused on improving the experience.

- Management of customer service area at a regional level (Chile, Colombia, Argentina) supporting the sales area from the customer's needs.
- Design of customer journey and identification of opportunities to improve the customer experience and increase sales through service as a differentiating factor.
- Implementation of the One service project for the region, centralizing the area in a single country.
 Thanks to this project, operating expenses were minimized, operational processes were improved, achieving an approximate saving of EUR 300K for the region.
- Design and planning of the CRM platform change for the region, including changes in a new service model.
- WOW project focused on improving the customer experience, designing customer journey and identifying opportunities, improving NPS, leadership of service OKRs, specialization of the telesales channel.
- Improvement of service indicators, training of the backoffice team focused on the key 3PS sellers for representing more than 30% of sales in their categories.
- Implementation of Dafity academy, a leadership program focused on customer service.

Project Manager, Planning and Continuous Improvement (PPP)

Development of strategies that ensure the growth of the business according to the established OKRs. Implementing new and continuous improvement projects, from benchmaking, financial evaluation, project feasibility study, design of new indicators and impact of existing ones, execution, evaluation and closure of projects. Among the successful projects, I highlight the following:

- New Dafiti distribution center (LATAM) project carried out from the analysis of the need for area for the growth plan, initial design of the requirements, achievement of the appropriate area, design of internal areas, bidding process with suppliers, leadership and monitoring of the execution teams, delivery and closure of the project. Capex was met, achieving savings of 20%, delivery times were met 100%, taking into account that it was executed during the COVID-19 health contingency.
- One service project focused on the centralization of the front office in a single country in the region, reducing operating costs by 40%, improving productivity.
- Project WOW, customer experience approach, managing to develop a project machine according to the
 customer's needs, resulting in an increase in NPS of 10 points, reducing delivery times and offering
 new services. Same day, Nextday.
- Implementation of HUB's cross-docking model for market place in major cities.
- Procurement and negotiation with conveyors for long haul (land and air), first mile and last mile.
- Implementation of the ADDI payment button.

Redes Eléctricas S.A. 2016- Feb 2019

Development Manager

Responsible for the growth of the company, identifying key processes of the company, improving and implementing new projects that generate an increase in sales and a better customer experience.

- Design and implementation of new logistics and warehousing processes.
- Re-design of the distribution center nationwide, including implementation of new warehouses in major cities. Leader of the project implementation of the E-commerce sales channel.

Dafiti Group August 2014- 2016

Assistant Content Manager

Operations leader, responsible for compliance with productivity indicators, area budget, negotiation with suppliers and B2B customer service.

SOLISTICA FEMSA

February 2009- August 2013

National Coordinator, Johnson Medical/Abbott

Solistica FEMSA, is a multinational company with offices in Mexico, Colombia, and Brazil in the sector of logistics operators in Storage, Transport, Customs, Maquilas, and Cold Chain. (3PL).

- Leader of consignments area.
- Management and coordination of inventories at the national level, ensuring the rotation and availability
 of medical equipment in clinics and hospitals.
- Reconciliation of inventories and introduction of new products due to technology changes, ensuring the movement and sale of existing ones.
- Coordination and management of returns and intra-hospital movements at the national level.

EDUCATION

- Master of Business Administration, Cardiff Metropolitan University, Malaysia 2013
- Industrial Engineer, Sergio Arboleda University, Colombia 2010
- Digital Marketing & Community Manager, Universidad EAFIT, Colombia 2014
- Web Design and Online Advertising, Cedinsi, Bogotá Colombia 2014

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native English: Advanced